Me dice ella que trabaja en una tienda de furniture y entonces le digo yo yo trabajo
aquí en el marina me dice oh le digo te dan comisión para la gente me dice sí y nada
le dije pasa por ahí me dice yo no puedo salir de la oficina pero te va a mandar la persona
que usualmente trabajan en esa parte de que deja los los brochures y todo eso y este muchacho
no lo viste no no no tenía un libro así de yo a mí muebles vienen de Italia y lo hacen
y de repente dice el que demora 6 to 8 weeks 6 to 8 weeks so anyways that's that one this is
juniors boyfriend
and this is juniors boyfriend and he does come and treat you see how beautiful that is he does this
remember what used to um el hermano de yorkies es lo que la este tipo ese tipo ajá si me he
shot how do you pronounce that yeah yeah yeah interiors that's because that's big business for
him and for lord of the so he's done yeah residential and yeah yeah like a boat yeah it's like a boat
and that's his company en juniors oh culetita cabinando así como cuando ella como una niña enamorada
pero estaba bonito muchacha estaba bueno estaba lindo
entonces le dije no pues traeme traeme formación yo yo le doy
a los muchachos y si te aceptan un trabajo me dice si yo se le digo que está bien
y ya bueno pero te estamos diciendo hay pobrecita carmen carmen que se está
muriendo de hambre en colorado que está un poquito deprimida que no no tiene no tiene donde
donde no no tiene nada que se siente un poquito
si hoy
hoy
sabes lo que se me olvidó pedirte hay que fueras al banco de positar el dinero que estaba ahí
que estaba un efectivo ahí en el al lado de michel que estaba un efectivo
pero no porque se me ayudó el amante para pedir para pedirte lo
pero si quería que lo fuera lo positar en tu cuenta de city bank
city bank si porque es que tengo un cheque contra city bank ahorita
que el viernes tengo que hacer efectos efectos
ay yo tengo una cita con una muchacha para hacerle los impuestos
pero mi prínter no funciona con todo el computador que tenemos
como no recuerdo el prínter que le dieron a mí y yo probé el prínter que tenemos ahora mismo
el que jose le dio a nosotros y lo que pasa con las otras máquinas
y las otras máquinas que no funcionan y no pueden usar la otra no funciona bien
no gano ink no it has ink no because it's not ink it's like a powder what it's a powder
powder polvo polvo es un polvo si se dice polvo powder polvo
es un polvo negro porque supuestamente es um laser
y eso es lo que dice y mismito en la careta dice fax they download they download
there is no downloading so how do you gonna pass from the from the computer to the
the thing work together i don't know that's what i have to do tonight i'll figure it out you can go home
because there is nothing up there there is nothing there yes that was what i did this morning to
to take you to lunch
so what i make more than last time how many hours did you work last time
no you didn't you couldn't have possibly made the same no why not 80 hours you worked last week
no i don't think so
okay 60 that that's it that's your difference right there
no how many hours 76 that's right no that's right because you're only looking at about 24 bucks
difference no a little bit more it was uh seven what seven something
seven looks hold on if you're looking at 12 times
80 80
so you had like 40 four hours more that's it you have four hours more four times 12
four times 12
so
I have one.
I don't know.
They finished employing someone to do the...
No one came to pick it up.
Oh, Pa.
Talk to them if...
I know they have a lot of applications,
but tell Luis that he wants to see the one from Miggia.
Poor thing.
Or my husband.
He's paying $6, $7 an hour.
And he...
They're trying to change the world.
There are so many people who didn't pick it up.
And what are they trying to save?
I don't know what they're trying to do.
I know they're doing something strange that nobody likes.
Who's doing it?
The office or Luis?
The office.
It's because they have them so tight.
With...
What's it called?
With the cable.
Oh, no, wait.
I told you yesterday...
I told you I was coming, but from the most...
The most crowded one.
Yesterday was the 7th.
Saying that the sales office...
I had told them to cross the street,
that we were going to do the...
The orientation.
So when she got there,
she says, you know,
I'm here to do my orientation.
I said, well, I'm sorry, but the office is closed.
We closed at 7.
Well, Caroline said, so call her right now.
I said, well, you know, Caroline doesn't do orientation,
but I can call my office right now.
So I picked up the phone and Maria...
I said, Maria, I have someone
who just finished closing,
and they told her to cross the street,
and that you would do an orientation.
Maria says, no, I'm closed.
I can't do an orientation.
I was told not to do any overtime.
So I proceeded to hang up the phone,
and I said, I'm so sorry.
The office is closed.
There's not much I can do.
And she just got all wired up,
and she's like, go, Caroline, go, Caroline.
And as she does this,
her boyfriend sees how...
or her friend out of life,
boyfriend or friend.
Do you call Caroline?
No, what for?
She was calling her cell phone.
And, you know,
I picked up the phone.
I gave her the number,
and she's verified the number that she had,
and I said, yeah, that's the number.
Let her call her.
Her boyfriend said, well, let's just go across the street.
So they went across the street and got Caroline.
Caroline was...
Well, Caroline was Caroline.
Walks all, you know,
huffing and puffing.
Yeah, come in, I see.
She looks like a little bird flying.
But, well, she doesn't fly.
Yes, yes.
At first, when she entered,
we need to go and pick up the bicycle.
Which one?
The one in Casa de...
Oh, okay.
Hey, wait a second, let me finish my story.
Yeah, go ahead.
What happened? Okay, so this whole story, right?
And then this morning she came.
Again?
Well, yeah, because we didn't do the orientation yesterday.
Mm-hmm.
And she made a complaint against me.
So, Kathy calls me.
She says, I have a resident
who just made a complaint about you.
And I said, well, Kathy,
that's why I came
into the office this morning
at 10.30 to tell you
I needed to speak to you.
She's like, oh, is it on the report?
I said, sure it is.
It's on the report today and yesterday.
She says, well, we need to extend
more courtesy. I said, hold on one second.
Did you see how excited she is?
Did you know how upset
she was yesterday?
Because they kept her four hours
just sitting there waiting for Caroline.
She's like, oh, you're right.
Okay.
Well,
she's like, okay, you, yeah,
I think you, okay, you did fine.
And that was it. But yeah, Kathy was
at first, you know, just dumping it on me.
And I was like, um,
this woman,
I wasn't going to stay.
I don't do orientation. I was like...
Yeah, and right in the front there
where you're sitting,
is Kathy's telephone number.
Yeah, but no, it wasn't my place
to call Catherine.
No, you know how to call nobody. You just give
the car to her.
No, no, I did. I gave her
the office car
and she didn't want it. She wanted
Caroline, so she went and got Caroline.
End of story. But then this morning
she was complaining about me and I was like,
why would she complain about me? It's not my
office. I don't do orientation.
She's like, well, I guess because you didn't
know. I was like, what do I have to call Karen?
And she had her on the cell phone.
So, anyways.
That was what happened today.
So it's a little
annoying, but then I was like, I'll get over it.
What's the worst thing that
can happen to me? I'll just walk
across the street and ask
the engineer there,
if they can give me a job.
Actually, if they offer me
12, 13
I will walk across the street.
Yeah, it's the same
same train. Same shit.
Different.
That's true. It's the same train.
I can just hop on and hop over
at the same time.
On Friday, I have to go with you
at 7.
You have to go and make
at 7 at work.
Why? Because I'm covering
for Carlos.
He's the most excited. He's happy.
He says they gave him that
internship.
What? The internship.
He's like an intern.
They don't pay him.
But they let him be
there in the studio.
He says he's never
done anything like that, but
he has to go in and see if everything
is clean, if something is missing,
if this is what he's
calling, if he's verifying.
But
he's in the studio.
That's where he wants to be.
Well, at least he's going to do
something he likes.
Yes.
Let's see what happens later.
I don't know if he's living
with his mother.
Yes.
That's why he's in the same
age as Padrasto.
Padrasto is the same age as him.
He's not going to be in the same age as
his husband or his son.
His mother.
But Padrasto is different.
They're two different relationships.
He's upset because
his mother is paying him the same
attention when he was alone.
Of course.
That's why he's upset.
It's because of the light.
It's bright. We can move over there.
No.
You want to move to the sofa?
Okay.
Well,
the only reason I kind of
figured it out was because
she said, oh yeah, Carlos
cooked.
Carlos went home.
And I'm thinking, oh,
Home, home.
Mommy's house.
So, anyways.
Miguel, I need you to call
the people for the
title.
What is the phone?
I don't know the phone number.
You mean to tell them
you paid $10
for them to do a title search.
The lady says we'll call you. Don't call us.
She could have just put those $10
in her pocket.
I'm so glad she gave her a receipt.
And that receipt,
surely there is a telephone number.
Maybe.
Could you find it, please? I need to know
what else is going on with that.
Did I show you how much I could pay?
I didn't get paid as much as you.
But I think this is
not by my short,
four-hour short. So, last week
you were four-hour short, this week I'm
four-hour short.
Because remember that
the day of training, they only paid me
for four hours?
So, that's going to be
eight.
But it doesn't matter because that's what
they paid. This is what counts.
This is what, the number
that we've got to look at.
Seven, eight, nine.
Put a hundred here and
seven is equal.
Seven, seven, fourteen.
And then you add this to the back
and this to the back.
So, I put the whole amount here.
What is this? What number is it?
So, the number that you're doing is
four.
Four is nine, carry the one.
Don't care nothing because it's five
and four is nine.
Why you have to carry something?
Because I don't care.
Okay, nine, that's 13, carry the one.
Six, seven, eight, nine.
And that would be eight.
And that would be
Ocho
Pones.
Fourteen.
Okay, so that's what we have right now.
And upstairs I have about
that much and then there is another envelope
with that.
That would be nine, that's still eight.
Five, six, seven, eight, nine.
Okay, so that's what I have right now.
What?
I know, but I'm always getting used to
counting one, two, three, four.
I don't know, I'm slow with that.
How do I know without actually
counting them?
Makes no sense.
Okay, so anyways,
I'm sure this
can be rounded off.
What?
Rounded off to nine.
And then I can round it off to two.
No.
Okay, forget it.
I don't have to do that.
Okay, listen.
This is what I need right now.
This is rent.
This is
insurance.
And this
is car payment.
That would be
four and
eleven, right?
Don't laugh at me.
It's weird, though.
Now, I still have no idea what
the registration to your vehicle is.
Salute.
You're so pig-ish.
Okay, so
rent, insurance, car.
I know,
just give me a few minutes.
Like what?
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
If it's not cash, no.
Okay.
That's only because you want to eat at a restaurant.
If I have to cook...
No, you don't have to be in the restaurant.
What do you want to do?
I'm talking about something that I like to eat.
I don't care where you eat.
I'm not talking about
your restaurant.
That's because it's the first thing that comes...
Yeah.
I'm talking about
a restaurant.
I'm talking about something that I like to eat.
I don't have to be in the restaurant.
Okay.
You want to eat?
I don't want to eat hot dogs.
I'm not going with you.
Where you going?
I don't have to eat hot dogs.
No, hasta mi estómago, sé por si.
Yo me comí un hotdog, oye?
De dos.
Ah, sí, lancos, sí.
De dos, ¿sí?
Del carrito ese que viene ahí.
El carrito tiene hotdogs.
Ajá.
¿Sí?
Sí, carrito ese de comida trae hotdogs.
Ven acá, ¿y cómo es que el otro que está un hotdog?
¿Sigo te traes almuerzo hoy?
No, pues, no fue a las hielas mañana.
No era la hora de comida, no, no.
Era un, no era hotdog.
Era una salsilla.
Parece una salsilla, sí.
Pero un pito largo, sí.
Ha, ha, ha.
Me costó $1.25.
Wow.
Oye, ¿sabes qué tengo que decirle al ballet
que los hotdogs del carrito están más barato y mejor seguro
que el hotdog del 7-Eleven que yo van y compran?
Ajá, pero el problema está del hotdog.
$1.25.
Y el pan es $1.25.
Y entonces tú coges, ¿no?
Tú harás el pan.
Ajá.
Y coges la cuchara que está ahí y busca la salsita que está.
La salsita que más te guste de toda la comida que está ahí.
Ojo la salsita.
Y por eso también te cobro.
¿Por la salsa, no?
Sí.
Si te cobro, pues, quiere decir que yo no tengo que comer pan
cuando yo como hotdog.
Mira qué bien.
A mí me gusta el pan cuando yo como hotdog.
Sí, por eso.
Me colegó un plato y ya...
No, no.
Imagínense, no, para comerse lo más que hotdog.
Entonces tú coges la salsita.
¿Qué están ahí?
Hay carne y tú una parte de cosas.
Hay carne en el salsita.
Sí, porque la salsa de la carne...
No hay chile.
Salsa de los bisteces que traen.
La salsa, la grasita con el bistec o de la otro.
O si no con un poco de frijoles,
tú usas entre salsitas y salsitas,
y se compras un poquito de carne también.
No.
Paua.
Y entonces coges el duro y yo lo muestro.
Ah, y lo cierve.
Y va a poner el tiempo y lo dice.
Dime cuánto es él.
Un 25.
Ok.
Eso Clarico me estaba diciendo que a ella le gustaba
porque te podías poner lo que...
El plato de ella le costó 2 dólares 50 centavos.
No, no, no.
Y tú te dejas la patea de la gana.
Eso es lo que ella dejó también y le dice, no.
Pongan la cazuela ahí.
Pongan la pinta.
Entonces tengo esta cantidad.
Lo que por ejemplo hay una...
Esa es mi cantidad para poner registración, comida
y lo demás.
¿Le ve?
La comida será así a un pez.
¿Qué?
Si empezó ¿dónde?
¿El refrigerador?
¿Ese refrigerador no se llena como si empezó?
Con menos.
Más.
Pero no hay que llenarlo tampoco, no es una misión llenando.
Ok, está ahí.
Ah.
Pero ahora ponte a pensar.
No lo llena.
Ok, está bien.
¿Tú has visto el refrigerador ahora?
¿Qué tiene?
Nada.
¿Dónde hay nada?
Dos huevos, creo que hay.
¿Hay que comprar huevos en todo?
Entonces, mira, hay menos ya.
Hay que comprar huevos.
Pero es lo que te digo, que...
Hemos estado apretando, lleno aquí, apretando allá, te dije,
me va a durar dos peches más, dos, dos pagos.
Van a estar aproximadamente aquí.
Este es el 28, 3, 28.
La primera renta se paga, este es este, y después aquí.
Esa es la primera renta.
¿Y dónde vamos a saber cómo estamos?
Financially.
Ya, desde este momento, al segundo que viene siendo 28,
probablemente como el 13.
Si me paga el 28,
entonces el próximo me da lo que viene siendo el 11.
Y me gustaría estar adelantada un poquito.
Entonces, 17 son 14, ¿verdad?
No.
Entonces son 1,400, lo cual me quedan 225 como crédito.
¿De acuerdo que ayer estábamos hablando de que si podemos...
Si puedo yo, aunque sea,
quedarme sin pagar renta un mes por adelantarme así,
porque cuando los niños vengan yo puedo pagar
para llevarlos al Disney World un tráfico.
¿A Disney World un tráfico?
Sí.
¿Por eso a mí?
No, pero solamente por un día, dos días.
¿Por un día, no?
No, tengo que quedarme en la noche con ellos,
imagínate tú tenés que manejar cinco horas.
Sale el viernes y llega al domingo.
Salimos el viernes, todos, ¿no quieres ir?
Sí, si no hay nada que hacer.
Vamos a ir con una niña y después con una niña.
¿Vamos a ir a Disney World con el niño y luego con el niño?
Sí, porque ella no viene a un tiempo.
So we have to go two times?
Oh yeah, it will be fun.
She's 13, 14, she's not going to like the same thing that he likes.
He's 17.
Oh, almost 17.
That's going to be a real challenge.
Why?
Look, they start in June 25th.
Say that I bring her the first week.
It doesn't matter if I bring her or him the first week,
until August.
Tengo junio, julio y agosto.
Si lo separo.
Esta es una semana.
Y una semana.
No importa en que mes.
Julio, agosto para el niño.
Creo que el niño se va a quedar más.
For how long she come?
She only comes for one week.
That's what she told me.
And for her, do you think he's going to be here longer than her?
He's going to want to stay longer.
Like two weeks?
Like three months.
Like three months?
Oh my.
I don't know.
He was talking about some stuff.
What kind of stuff?
No, his dad is just mean.
Yeah.
Le escribió.
¿Quién le escribió a quién?
Una carta al niño, Robert.
Robert escribió una carta al niño?
Robert escribió una carta al niño.
¿Y qué dice la carta?
Suena muy frustrado de que si tú vives en mi casa gratis,
tú no estás haciendo estas cosas,
limpiar su cuarto, hacer esto, será que yo.
Y entonces me dice, mami, yo no estoy aquí gratis.
Yo voy, trabajo.
Y el dinero que se agarra en esta casa,
yo hago más, y al niño sabe.
Dice, yo hago más.
Y traigo, y mira cómo él me dice a mí,
que cómo es que yo vivo aquí en esta casa gratis.
Después me dice, porque tú tienes teléfono,
y entonces tú te la pasas en Ninja Monkey.
Y me dice, yo pago mi teléfono, el niño.
Entonces me dice, mami, es que yo trato de ser positivo
y de no hacerle casas a mi papá,
él dice cosas que me frustra y dice, yo no sé qué decir.
Le digo, no le digas nada, papá,
tú eres menor de edad todavía.
No, no, no, y aunque seas mayor de edad,
no puedes ir en otro, papá.
No, yo creo que le entiende esa parte,
pero es de eso que él se siente como que él lo está...
He's letting him down, his father,
he's letting his father down.
I think that's what frustrates him the most.
So when I tell him, just come and live with me.
The problem?
He says that my father is just going to say
I'm running away from my problem,
which is true what he's going to say.
All one, letting him to decide.
The moment is going to come anyway.
The moment is going to come, but it's going to be ugly.
Ah, well.
El niño no va a querer hablar con padre,
él no va a querer saber de padre.
That's not the problem.
The problem is that the father is trying to do the same
that he do when he was the baby's age.
No, no, Robert never has wanted mucho así, así tampoco.
No creo.
¿A qué edad, Robert, salió de la casa?
Robert salió de la casa a las 13.
A los 13?
13 años.
Ah, no, ya, ya, ya.
Entonces, ya más está trazado ya.
Max viene trabajando para su padre,
porque desde que tenía 13.
No, bueno.
Si eso fue uno de las primeras excusas
que él usó cuando él mandó al niño a trabajar,
le digo no, no, no, dejan niño en paz.
Me dice, no, si yo trabajo a los 13.
Me da mucho que tan grande estar.
Ajá, exactamente.
Eso es lo que va a hacer el niño.
Ay, Robert, pero es que yo no quiero que él se...
No, es problema de que tú quieras, no quieras.
Sí.
Si Robert se salió de su casa a los 13 años,
y el niño tiene 16 y está en la casa todo día.
Y arriba de eso está haciendo las carticas esas de...
de Prusciese.
I know, I know I am like that.
Pero sí es normal.
Eso es lo que tenemos nosotros de unos hijos, ¿no?
No, no, no.
Max is a real responsible kid.
Exactamente.
I mean, I'm not saying that it's right,
but you know, he could be doing so many others,
but he could be, besides failing,
because, well, he is failing us over his class.
He...
Okay, let's think about a normal family.
No normal kid runs a company.
Let's just not call it a company.
No normal kid would be able to pick up a phone,
talk to another adult, let him know what town
the job is going to have,
call employees and tell them what time
they need to be somewhere at 40 and 50.
You got kids that they only think of...
No, no, no, no kid.
Yes kid.
Look at me.
I wait time to get out of my house.
What do you mean?
¿A qué da yo salir de mi casa?
No, no.
¿Cómo los 21 años?
¿Cuánto puede haber ese?
¿Tú no trabajaste tú eso a la escuela?
Sí, a la escuela, a la escuela.
La escuela no tiene nada que ver.
Después de salir de la escuela,
que empecé a trabajar,
que tenía mujer y decía yo que yo era un hombre,
todo yo estaba en mi casa.
Y cuando me fajaba como mujer salía corriendo por mi casa.
Cuando venía a trabajar del campo,
24, 26,
yo iba a la casa de una mujer,
que es la casa de una mujer.
Mi casa es la casa de mi mamá.
Mi casa es mi mujer viviendo y todo ya.
Sí, sí, aquí llegué.
Mira, aquí hay comida, comida.
En Cuba es comida.
Cuba no es caro, mi zapato, mi ropa.
Comida, comida, comida, comida, comida.
Voy a mi casa a llevar la otra parte de la comida.
Tú lo llevas a comer a tu mamá.
Ajá.
Como mi mamá no le gusta la sucedad,
pues yo traía los animales vivos
y lo mataba allá.
Ah.
Y llegué a mi casa allá con la carne limpia.
Con la carne limpia, sí.
Claro.